naviance.com 2016-07-12

# Privacy Policy | Naviance

**PLEASE NOTE: This Privacy Policy does not apply to our software products**.  For information about those privacy policies, please refer to the privacy policies as follows:

If you are located outside of the United States, please be aware that the information you provide to us is transmitted to and processed in the United States. Data will be protected subject to this Privacy Policy and applicable law, which may be different from the laws in your country. By using this Site, you agree to this. 

#### Information We Collect

On certain areas of our Site, we offer features where users may provide us with their personal information in order to subscribe to a newsletter, obtain more information about our products and services, participate in a survey, post comments on a blog post, contact us or otherwise voluntarily submit information to us.  The information requested in order for us to deliver these features includes your first and last name, email address, and in some cases your school name and other information that you may choose to provide. 

Additionally, as part of the standard operation of the Site, we may also collect certain “Site Usage Information.”  Site Usage Information is non-personal information from you, including but not limited to your browser type, operating system, IP address and the domain name from which you accessed the Site.  It may also include information about your browsing behavior, such as the date and time you visit the Site, the areas or pages of the Site that you visit, the amount of time you spend viewing the Site, the number of times you return to the Site and other “click-stream” data.  We do not combine this non-personal information with your personal information. 

We use this information to: (1) administer the Site, monitor its usage and diagnose problems with it; (2) remember you when you return to the Site, so that you do not have to re-submit information and preferences; and (3) improve our content and services.  In addition, we use software that uses your IP address to determine roughly where you are located so that we can customize the site based on your region.

We use the following tracking technologies to collect the Site Usage Information described above:

Cookies:  A cookie is a small data file that may be sent by a website or application and stored on the hard drive of your computer.  A cookie stores information about your browser that allows us to recognize your browser when you return to our site and to remember your preferences.  You are free to decline cookies, but by doing so, you may not be able to use certain features on the website or take full advantage of all of our offerings.  To learn more about browser cookies, including how to manage or delete them, check the “Help,” “Tools” or similar section of your browser.

Pixel tags:  A pixel tag (also known as a “clear GIF” or “web beacon”) is a tiny image that can be placed on a website page or in an email.  We use pixel tags to help us measure the effectiveness of our e-mail campaigns, by telling us whether the messages have been received, opened or otherwise acted upon.

We use a third party service provider to assist us in collecting and understanding Site Usage Information.  By using our Site, you agree to our use of these tracking technologies.

#### Third-Party Tracking, Ad Servers and Networks

Third parties, such as ad networks, web analytics companies and social networking platforms, may collect information about your online activities over time and across our Site and other third party sites and online services.  This information is used to provide advertisements for products and services that may interest you.  These advertisements may appear when you browse on other websites, and those companies may use cookies, clear GIF’s and other tracking technologies. 

For information about the privacy practices of third party advertising companies who serve ads on our behalf, visit <http://www.google.com/policies/privacy>.  For more information about third-party advertisers and how to prevent them from using your information, visit the NAI’s consumer site at <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices> or <http://www.aboutads.info/choices>.

We do not honor “do not track” signals transmitted by users’ web browsers, so we encourage you to visit these links if you would like to opt out of certain tracking.  Note that you need to opt out separately for each of your devices and for each Web browser you use on each device.

#### How We Use Information

We may use the information we collect from and about you for any of the following purposes:  (1) to fulfill your requests for products and services; (2) to customize site content for your region; (3) to contact you with information and promotional materials from our company as well as from our affiliates, other related companies, educational institutions, marketing partners and other third parties when you have agreed to receive such communications; (4) to contact you when necessary for legal or security purposes; (5) to review Site and product usage and operations; (6) to address problems with the Site, improve our business or our products and services; and (7) to protect the security or integrity of the Site and our business. 

We do not retain your personal information longer than necessary to provide you with the services you have requested.  We do retain aggregated, non-personally identifiable information for some of the purposes described above.

#### Information Disclosure

In addition to the uses described above, we may disclose your information for the following purposes:  (1) to our service providers, who may use it only on our behalf to provide our web services; (2) as necessary, if we believe that there has been a violation of our website Terms & Conditions or of our rights or the rights of any third party; (3) to respond to judicial process and provide information to law enforcement agencies or in connection with an investigation as permitted by law, or otherwise as required by law; (4) as disclosed to you at the point of collection; and (5) in the event of a reorganization, merger, sale, assignment, bankruptcy or other disposition of our business, in which case the transferred information will remain subject to the terms of this Privacy Policy.

Any personal information or content that you voluntarily upload or submit for posting to a Site (including your name and information in your comments) becomes publicly available and can be collected and used by others.  It may also be available to third party search engines.  It is in violation of the Site’s Terms & Conditions for you to post any content that requests personally identifiable information.

We may share aggregate, non-personally identifiable information about you with third parties for research and other purposes.

#### Links

The Site includes links to other sites, which are provided for your convenience only.  Our inclusion of these third party sites on our Site does not imply our approval or endorsement.  We have no control over these linked sites, all of which have their own privacy policies and terms of use, which we encourage you to read.

#### Social Networking

Tools in some areas of our Site allow you to share content through a third-party social networking site.  In using these tools, you may be providing information to those third party sites.  Please note that third party social networks have their own privacy policies and terms of use, and we encourage you to read them.

#### Security

Hobsons has implemented technical, administrative and physical security measures designed to secure your information.  We utilize a third party provider to store and process your personal information, and that provider has also implemented robust physical, electronic, contractual and managerial steps to safeguard and secure your personal information.  This includes transmission of data via HTTPS and restrictions on access to the data.  The Internet, however, is not perfectly secure and we are not responsible for security breaches not reasonably within its control.

#### How You Can Access and Modify Information

To access, correct or request that we make no further use of personal information you may have provided to us via this website, please send us an [e-mail](mailto:privacypolicy@hobsons.com) or contact us by mail at 50 E-Business Way, Suite 300 Cincinnati, OH 45241.

For information about how to access, correct or request that we make no further use of personal information you may have provided to us via one of our products, please refer to the privacy policy for that product.

California law permits residents of California to request certain details about how their information is shared with third parties for direct marketing purposes. If you are a California resident and would like to make such a request, please contact us at privacypolicy@Hobsons.com

#### Opt Out Policy

You may opt out of receiving commercial e-mail from us at any time by following the instructions in each e-mail or by contacting us by mail at 50 E-Business Way, Suite 300 Cincinnati, OH 45241.

#### Children

We do not direct the Site to, nor do we knowingly collect any personal information from, children under the age of 13. Should we learn that we have inadvertently collected personal information from children under the age of 13, we will take steps to delete it immediately.

#### Updates to this Policy

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time.  When we do, we will let you know by posting the changed Policy on this page with a new “Last Updated” date.  If we change the Privacy Policy in a material way, we will provide appropriate notice to you as required by law.  In some cases, we may require your consent to the changes.

#### Contact Us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at:

**Privacy Team**  
Hobsons  
50 E-Business Way, Suite 300  
Cincinnati, OH 45241  
Phone: 800.927.8439

Naviance.com uses cookies to improve your experience. By using our services, you’re agreeing to our Cookie Policy.
